Gauray Patel



patelgaurav1202@gmail.com



9369058779



linkedin.com/in/gaurav-patel-9662753b



https://gauravprofile.netlify.app/

Summary

I am working as a Tech Lead in enquero, and involved in developing and maintaining projects in various sizes in order to enhance capabilities and efficiency besides utilizing my skills in a technical industry having scope to learn and grow".

Worked with Web Services and implemented it in projects and UI implemented.

Extensively used JavaScript framework JQuery to build Ajax driven web applications.

Good communication and quick learning skills are my strengths.

Specialties: Javascript, Angular JS/2/4/5/6, React JS, redux, MySQL, Apache, Jquery, Web Services, HTML5, CSS3, node JS, express JS, Java Core,

Experience

Lead Software Engineer

Enquero

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

Angular + React JS, Vue js, redux Lead software developer

Demonstrate strong software design and development skills and passion to develop scalable web applications.

Work with team (Developer(s), Technical Architect, Service

Delivery Manager) to review and understand incoming work items and estimate time appropriately, with minimum guidance from mentors as and when required.

- Translate technical requirements into reality following best practices.
- Work in an agile DevOps team owning and operating the services you build.
- Analyse requirement and identify gaps/ambiguities in requirements.
- Proactive and thorough communication with team members.

SONICWALL SE

Senior Software Engineer

SonicWall

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020 (8 months)

Result oriented Software engineer various aspects of design and Development.

Demonstrate strong software design and development skills and passion to develop scalable web applications.

Market Software Engineer

Nalashaa Solutions

Sep 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Result oriented Software engineer various aspects of design and Development.

Demonstrate strong software design and development skills and passion to develop scalable web applications.

Front End developer

Lendingkart

Feb 2017 - Sep 2017 (8 months)

Result oriented Software engineer various aspects of design and Development.

Demonstrate strong software design and development skills and passion to develop scalable web applications.

Front End developer

Fortunesoft IT Innovations

Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Result oriented Software engineer various aspects of design and Development.

Demonstrate strong software design and development skills and passion to develop scalable web applications.

Education



Kanpur Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Information Technology

2010 - 2014

B.Tech

Harishchandra Inter College Varanasi

Inter (10+2), Mathematics

2008 - 2010

Mathematics and Computer Science

Jeevandeep Public School Varanasi

High School, Mathematics and Computer Science

2006 - 2008

Mathematics and Computer Science

Licenses & Certifications



AMCAT Certified Proficiency in English - Aspiring Minds

878808-284

Skills

React.js • Angular 6 • Python (Programming Language) • Data Structures • Algorithms • Web Development • Web Services • Front-end Development • Software Development • Agile Methodologies